investec.co.za 2012-05-28

# Privacy Policy - Investec Specialist Bank

### About this Privacy Policy

This Policy sets out how we use and protect any personal information that you give us when you use this website and any associated microsites in particular jurisdictions (set out in the table at the end of this Policy) or any applications. Please refer to the end of this Policy for any additional terms relevant to your jurisdiction.  

If you have any questions about this Policy or do not agree with it, please contact us by [clicking here](mailto:grouponlinemarketing@investec.co.uk) before using this website. We may change this Policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure you are happy with any changes. This Policy is effective from 12 December 2011.  

By accessing any part of this website or providing information to us you consent to the use and transfer of such information by us on the terms set out in this Policy.  

This Policy augments and should be read in conjunction with the relevant Data Protection Statement set out at Data Protection ("DP Statement").  

The DP Statement forms part of this Policy. To the extent that there is a direct conflict between the DP Statement of the relevant entity and this Policy, the DP Statement of the relevant entity shall prevail.  

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect on line. We use encryption when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information.  

**1\. Information We Collect from You  
**

In general, you can use this website without giving us any information. Any domain name information that we collect is not used to personally identify you but is instead aggregated to measure the number of visits, average time spent on the website, pages viewed. We use this information to measure the use of our website and to improve its contents. However, additional services may be available if we have certain information about you.  

We may collect the following information:

  * any information which you are asked for in the registration section of this website, for the purposes of registering your use of any of our online services;  

  * a list of the products and services you indicate an interest in (if you register with us to use our online services);  

  * your name and contact information, including email address and company details;  

  * information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experiences with our products and contact preferences in order to provide you with further correspondence about our products and services.  

Personal information we collect automatically:

  * When you use the website, we automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser or mobile platform, including your location, IP address, cookie information, and the page you requested.  

  * We treat this data as non-Personal Information, except where we are compelled to do otherwise by law or legal authority.  

  * We only use this data in aggregate form and we may provide this aggregate information to our partners about how our customers, collectively, use the website, so that our partners may also understand how users make use of the website.  
We may intercept and monitor your communications:  

  * We may implement systems designed to intercept and monitor your communications with Investec Associates, to the extent permissible by law, in which case you consent to such interception and monitoring.  

  * As part of this process of intercepting and monitoring these communications, we may record such communications for disclosure on the basis set out in this Policy.  

**2\. What We Do With The Information  
**

We use this information to provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * providing services you have requested and notifying you about important changes or developments to these services;  

  * responding to your inquiries and complaints or to process your requests in relation to your information;  

  * to follow up as part of our customer care procedures;  

  * updating our records about you;  

  * internal record keeping;  

  * administering offers;  

  * to improve our products and services;  

  * crime detection prevention and prosecution;  

  * competitions and other promotions;  

  * evaluating the effectiveness of our marketing and for research, training and statistical analysis with the aim of improving our services;  

  * making our website easier for you to use and providing you with access to certain parts of the website; and  

  * to contact you for market research purposes.

At the time you provide us with any information in response to a request from us, our request will provide you with specific information as to how we will use such information.  

Other than for the direct marketing purposes referred to below, we may contact you by e-mail, phone, fax or mail in relation to the purposes set out in this section and by providing such information you are deemed to have agreed to us contacting you by these methods of communication. We will continue to contact you by way of such methods until you advise us in writing you no longer wish to be contacted by certain methods. Please note you are required to accept at least one of the above methods as your chosen method of receipt of communication from us.

We will not pass your details to anyone else (other than on the basis set out below and in accordance with appropriate disclosure requirements we may be subject to).  

**3\. Direct Marketing**

We would like to provide you with information about new products, promotions, special offers and other information which we think you may find interesting. We may send you such information by email, post or telephone where you have opted to receive such marketing materials and have indicated to us how you wish to receive such marketing material when you registered for our services. If you have let us know that you do not want your information used for direct marketing purposes we will not send you any direct marketing.  

If we are providing you with services you will also be subject to the specific terms and conditions relating to the product and/or services you are being provided with and these terms will include additional information as to how we may contact you.  

If you have signed up to receive marketing material from us through specific methods, we will continue to provide this information by such method unless you ask us not to do so.  

You can change your mind at any time by contacting the Investec Plc and Investec Bank Plc Data Protection Compliance Officer at 2 Gresham St, London EC2V 7QP, or the Investec Wealth and Investment Limited Data Protection Officer at 100 Old Hall Street, Liverpool, L3 9AB, or the Investec Asset Finance Plc Data Protection Officer at Windrush Court, Blacklands Way, Abingdon, Oxfordshire, OX14 1SY.  

**4\. Email marketing**

We would also like to provide you with the information above by email. However, we appreciate that email “spam” has become a problem in recent years.  

If you are a customer or you have previously asked us for information on our products, we may send you information on our range of products by email where we have your permission to do so.  

If the reason you have given us personal information is to receive email information from us, we will continue to provide this information by email unless you ask us not to do so.  
If, in providing us with your personal information you have agreed to us using such information to provide you with details of products or services that we consider may be of interest to you by way of e-mail, we will continue to provide this information by e-mail unless you ask us not to do so.  

If you are a new customer, we will only send you marketing information by e-mail if, as part of the registration for our on-line services, you have agreed to the receipt of marketing material from us on such a basis.  

If we are providing you with services, you will also be subject to the specific terms and conditions relating to the product and/or services you are being provided with and these terms will include additional information as to how we may contact you.  

We will continue to provide you with marketing material through by specific methods of communication where you have signed up to the applicable preference service in respect of such method.  

**5\. Linking  
**

We may link to other websites which are not within our control. Once you have left our website, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.  

**6\. Cookies**

As we mentioned above, we use cookies on our website. Cookies are files that store information on your hard drive or browser that means that our website can recognise that you have visited our website before. They make it easier for you to maintain your preferences on the website, and by seeing how you use the website, we can tailor the website around your preferences and measure usability of the website. You can, should you choose, disable the cookies from your browser and delete all cookies currently stored on your computer. You can find out how to do this for your particular browser by clicking "help" on your browser's menu or by clicking here.  

**7\. Sharing Your Information  
**

We will not transfer, disclose, sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties other than on the following basis:

  * where we have your permission;  

  * to our subsidiaries, associated companies or parent company (or subsidiaries thereof) or a purchaser or potential purchaser of our business;  

  * where we are required to do so by law;  

  * where it is needed by our agents, advisors or others involved in running accounts and services for you or in undertaking activities linked to the operation of such services or accounts on our behalf; or  

  * where the transfer or disclosure would otherwise be in compliance with legal requirements we are subject to including, but not limited to, statute or regulation.

This process may include sending personal information to other countries, whose data protection laws may not be as extensive as in the European Economic Area. However, we have taken appropriate steps to ensure the same level of protection for the processing carried out in these countries as within the European Economic Area.

**8\. Accessing Your Personal Information  
**

If you think any information we have about you is incorrect or incomplete, please write or e-mail us as soon as possible at the relevant addresses set out below. We will correct or update any information as soon as possible.

For Users in Australia  

For Users in Ireland  

For users in South Africa  
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Promotion of Access to Information Act 2000. Fees for access to your personal information are prescribed in terms of this Act. If you would like to obtain a copy of your personal information held by Investec Limited, please review our Promotion of Access to Information Act Manual located at http://investec.com/legal/paia-promotion-of-access-to-information-act.html.  

For users in the United Kingdom  
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you by Investec plc and/or Investec Bank plc please write to our Data Protection Compliance Officer at 2 Gresham St, London EC2V 7QP. If you would like a copy of the information held on you by Investec Wealth and Investment Limited, please write to our Data Protection Compliance Officer at 100 Old Hall Street, Liverpool, L3 9AB. If you would like a copy of the information held on you by Investec Asset Finance Plc, Please write to our Data Protection Compliance Officer at Windrush Court, Blacklandsway, Abingdon, Oxfordshire, OX14 1SY.  

**9\. Additional Terms  
**

Australia  
(www.investec.co.au)  
If you are viewing this website in Australia it is provided by Investec Bank (Australia) Limited (Company Number: ABN 55 071 292 594). The Terms and the use of this website are governed by the laws of the Commonwealth of Australia and any disputes will be decided only by the Courts of the Commonwealth of Australia.  

Ireland  
(www.investec.co.ie)  
If you are viewing this website in Ireland it is provided by Investec Ireland Limited (Company Number: 232526). The Terms and the use of this website are governed by the laws of Ireland and any disputes will be decided only by the courts of Ireland.

Mauritius  
(www.investec.com)  
If you are viewing this website in Mauritius it is provided by Investec Bank (Mauritius) Limited (Company Number: 8752/3362). The Terms and the use of this website are governed by with laws of Mauritius and any disputes will be decided only by the courts of Mauritius.

South Africa  
(www.investec.co.za)  
If you are viewing this website in South Africa it is provided by Investec Bank Limited (Company Number:   ). The Terms and the use of this website are governed by the laws of South Africa and any disputes will be decided only by the courts of South Africa.

United Kingdom  
(www.investec.co.uk)  
If you are viewing this website in the United Kingdom it is provided by Investec Bank plc (Company Number: 00489604). The Terms and the use of this website are governed by the laws of England and Wales and any disputes will be decided only by the courts of England and Wales.

United States of America and Canada  
(www.investec.com)  
If you are viewing this website in the United States and Canada it is provided by [    ] (Company Number:    ). The Terms and the use of this website are governed by [   ].  

Additional Terms:  
You should not be viewing this website from any jurisdiction that is not listed above.
